by the time the atomic bombs fell in
August 1945 Japan's defeat was clear to
all but the most fanatical generals its
once vast Empire lay in Ruins its Navy
and Air Force were decimated and its
population faced starvation under a
cripping US blockade American
firebombing had Unleashed destruction
across the country claiming over 260,000
lives and leaving 13 million people
homeless the Relentless aerial
bombardment Contin continued with nearly
daily raids devastating The Battered
Nation although some government figures
particularly foreign minister Shori Togo
now favored a diplomatic resolution to
the war they were outnumbered by
Hardline militarists who continued to
dictate Japan's policy peace discussions
remained covert and centered on
unrealistic terms that would never be
accepted by the Allies the Japanese
government was effectively under the
control of the military and